Ahmed Mansour

New Cairo, Egypt | +20 1012070920 | ahmedsmansour@proton.me | mansourweb.github.io

Summary

Full Stack Python developer with cloud computing (AWS) and Linux administration experience. Open to global opportunities and relocation, with a diverse perspective from living in Egypt, Azerbaijan, the Philippines, and Cameroon.

Skills

Languages: proficient in Python, Bash, HTML, CSS; familiar with C++, SQL

DevOps: AWS architecture & core services, Terraform, Red Hat Linux administration, Networking protocols & security

Tools: Git, Django, Pytest, Beautiful Soup, Selenium, Bootstrap *Certifications:* currently pursuing AWS SAA-C03 and RHCSA

Experience

Systems Administrator, Egyptian Police Academy – Conscription

Oct 2021 - Dec 2022

- Developed local Python scripts via WSL to automate watermarking, file encryption, and employee query retrieval
- Maintained 99% uptime by managing internal DNS records and administering user/group permissions for file servers
- Improved department efficiency by providing software training, resulting in higher post-assessment scores amongst staff

Software Engineer Intern, Opatrip Lithuania – Remote

Jan 2021 – Aug 2021

- Reduced manual data entry by 50%: automated import, population, and updates for 200+ tours via Google Sheets' API
- Increased customer conversion rates by integrating multicurrency functionality with the Bokun backend, leveraging JSON and RESTful APIs

Systems Analyst Intern, TBS, Birds Cage Food Products, Givaudan – Academic

Feb 2019 - Dec 2020

- Tackled workflow bottlenecks with tailored prototypes and database solutions for transaction & decision-support systems
- Delivered feasible project implementation and planning through cost-benefit analysis, ERD/DFD analysis, risk assessments, Gantt scheduling, and comprehensive SRS documentation

Projects

Global VPN Accelerator

CloudFormation, EC2, TGW, VPC, Global Network, IPsec tunnels, FRR, BGP

- Deployed an AWS site-to-site VPN that allows remote users access to a simulated corporate network via IPsec tunnels
- Enabled fast route exchange with AWS by implementing BGP capabilities using FRR on the on-premises routers
- Increased network speeds by using globally accelerated VPN endpoints attached to a transit gateway

Elastic Press

VPC, EC2, SSM Parameters, IAM, Launch Templates, RDS, EFS, ELB, ASG

- Transformed a single instance WordPress server to an automatically provisioned deployment via launch templates
- Ensured prolonged data lifespan through MySQL migration to RDS and storing local media on an EFS shared file system
- Maintained uninterrupted service and scalability by using ASG and ELB, scaling based on CPU load during peak demand

MindScribe

Python, Django, Bootstrap, Git, YAML

- Built a full-stack app to track learning progress, implementing Django authentication and content filtering based on user
- Achieved cross-device compatibility with Bootstrap and deployed the app on Platform.sh with custom error pages

Education

The American University in Cairo – B.B.A. in Information Systems

June 2021

• Relevant Coursework: OOP, Data Structures and Algorithms, Languages and Compilers, Database Design, Software Engineering, Information Systems & Security, Business Analysis, Project Management